A Perfect Day is a comedy, drama, war film directed by Fernando León de Aranoa.
Somewhere in the Balkans, 1995.
A team of aid workers must solve an apparently simple problem in an almost completely pacified territory that has been devastated by a cruel war, but some of the
local inhabitants, the retreating combatants, the UN forces, many cows and an absurd bureaucracy will not cease to put obstacles in their way.
Mambrú, played by Benicio del Toro.
B, played by Tim Robbins.
Katya, played by Olga Kurylenko.
Sophie, played by Mélanie Thierry.
Damir, played by Feđa Štukan.
Nicola, played by Eldar Rešidović.
A Perfect Day is a 2015 Spanish comedy-drama film written
and directed by Fernando León de Aranoa.
It is based on the novel Dejarse Llover by Paula Farias.
It was screened in the Directors' Fortnight section at the 2015 Cannes
Film Festival and is the director's English-language debut.
The film explores themes of bosnia and herzegovina, road trip,
bosnian war (1992-95), united nations, 1990s.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.